Is it true that our brain alone is responsible for human cognition?
人类的认知真的只由我们的大脑负责吗？
What about our body?
那我们的身体呢？
Is it possible for thought and behavior to originate from somewhere other than our brain?
思维和行为有没有可能源自大脑以外的其他地方？
Psychologists who study Embodied Cognition (EC) ask similar questions.
研究具身认知（EC）的心理学家也提出了类似的问题。
The EC theory suggests our body is also responsible for thinking or problem-solving.
EC理论认为，我们的身体同样负责思考或解决问题。
More precisely, the mind shapes the body and the body shapes the mind in equal measure.
更确切地说，心智塑造身体，身体也以同等程度塑造心智。
If you think about it for a moment, it makes total sense.
只要你稍微想一想，就会发现这完全说得通。
When you smell something good or hear amusing sounds, certain emotions are awakened.
你闻到好闻的气味或听到有趣的声音时，某些情绪就会被唤起。
Think about how newborns use their senses to understand the world around them.
想想新生儿是如何利用感官来认识周围世界的。
They don’t have emotions so much as needs—they don’t feel sad, they’re just hungry and need food.
与其说他们有情绪，不如说他们有需求——他们不会感到难过，只是饿了，需要食物而已。
Even unborn babies can feel their mothers’ heartbeats and this has a calming effect.
甚至还未出生的婴儿都能感受到母亲的心跳，而这能起到安抚作用。
In the real world, they cry when they’re cold and then get hugged.
来到现实世界后，他们冷了就会哭，然后就会有人把他们抱起来。
That way, they start to associate being warm with being loved.
这样一来，他们便开始把温暖和被爱联系在一起。
Understandably, theorists have been arguing for years and still disagree on whether the brain is the nerve centre that operates the rest of the body.
可以理解的是，理论家们多年来一直争论不休，对于大脑是否就是操控身体其余部分的神经中枢，至今仍意见不一。
Older Western philosophers and mainstream language researchers believe this is fact, while EC theorises that the brain and body are working together as an organic supercomputer, processing everything and forming your reactions.
早期的西方哲学家和主流的语言研究者认为，大脑确实就是操控身体的神经中枢，而EC理论则认为，大脑和身体作为一台有机的超级计算机协同工作，处理一切并形成你的反应。
Further studies have backed up the mind-body interaction.
进一步的研究证实了这种身心互动。
In one experiment, test subjects were asked to judge people after being handed a hot or a cold drink.
在一项实验中，实验对象先被递上一杯热饮或冷饮，随后被要求对他人作出评判。
They all made warm evaluations when their fingertips perceived warmth rather than coolness.
当指尖感受到的是暖意而不是凉意时，他们全都给出了友善的评价。
And it works the other way too; in another study, subjects had their fingertip temperatures measured after being “included” in or “rejected” from a group task.
而且反过来也成立：在另一项研究中，实验对象在一项小组任务中被“接纳”或被“排斥”之后，接受了指尖温度测量。
Those who were included felt physically warmer.
被接纳的人感觉身体更暖和。
For further proof, we can look at the metaphors that we use without even thinking.
要找更多证据，我们可以看看那些自己不假思索就会用到的比喻说法。
A kind and sympathetic person is frequently referred to as one with a soft heart, and someone who is very strong and calm in difficult situations is often described as solid as a rock.
善良而富有同情心的人常被称为“心肠软”的人，而在困境中非常坚强、镇定的人则常被形容为“坚如磐石”。
And this kind of metaphorical use is common across languages.
而且这类比喻性用法在各种语言中都很常见。
Now that you have the knowledge of mind-body interaction, why not use it?
既然你已经了解了身心互动，何不加以利用呢？
If you’re having a bad day, a warm cup of tea will give you a flash of pleasure.
如果你今天过得不顺，一杯热茶会给你带来片刻的愉悦。
If you know you’re physically cold, warm up before making any interpersonal decisions.
如果你知道自己身体发冷，那么在做任何涉及人际关系的决定之前，先让自己暖和起来。